Adams Family Papers, 1712-1889 Ms 27 Ms 27
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Adams Family Papers, 1712-1889
Ms 27
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.75 linear ft.
Collection of legal and financial papers spanning the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries from the Adams family of Fairfield, CT.
(2 boxes, 1725 items)
Adams family
Adams, Edward Bradford
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
The Adams family came to Fairfield in the 1650's and later settled in Green's Farms and Westport around 1700. Family members were landowners, farmers, storekeepers, school teachers and bankers. For a published genealogy see The History of Fairfield, Vol. I. by Elizabeth Schenck, 1889.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of one and a half boxes. Boxes I, Folders A-D hold deeds. In Folder A, Moses Knap's and John Crissy's deeds dates refer to Queen Anne's reign. Folder E contains legal papers; Folder F bills and bills receipted; Folder G financial papers, correspondence and maps; and Folder H through I account books. Of particular note in in Folder E is a contract for a negro boy. Box II, Folder A holds a genealogy book.
Adams, Eli, 1784-1861; Adams, Joseph; Adams, Nathan; Addams, Nathaniel; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County--Maps.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Receipts (financial records)
- Deeds, 1712-1749; Box I, Folder A; 15.0 items
  - From Peter Clapham to Nathan Addams, 1723
  - From John Hall to Nathan Addams Jr., 1712
  - From Abraham Adams Jr. to Nathan Addams Jr., 1712
  - From Moses Knap to Nathan Adams, 1713
  - From Nathan Addams Jr. to Nathan Addams, 1714
  - From John Sturgis to Nathan Addams Jr., 1714
  - From John Crissy to Nathan Adams, 1714
  - From David Morehouse, et al. to Nathan Adams, 1716
  - From Dougal and Sarah Mackenzie to Nathan Addams Jr., 1721
  - From Benjamin Sturgis to Nathan Adams, 1736, 1737; 3.0 items
  - From Lewis and Sarah MackDaniels to Nathan Adams, 1740
  - From Jehial Lockwood to Nathan Adams, 1747, 1749; 2.0 items
- Deeds, 1750-1783; Box I, Folder B; 19.0 items
  - From to Nathan Adams to Nathaniel Adams, 1750, 1751; 2.0 items
  - From A committee to Nathaniel Adams, 1750
  - From Thad Burr to Nathaniel Adams, 1750
  - From John Burr II to Nathaniel Adams, 1750
  - From Ebenezer and Rebecah Mead to Nathaniel Addams, 1755
  - From Joshua Jennings to Nathaniel Adams, 1756, 1760, 1770; 4.0 items
  - From John Hurlbutt to Nathaniel Adams, 1759
  - From Thaddeus Morehouse to Nathaniel Adams, 1764
  - From Nathaniel Adams to Nathaniel Adams Jr., 1767
  - From Nathan Adams to Nathaniel Adams, 1770
  - From Jabez Morehouse to Nathaniel Adams, 1772, 1773; 2.0 items
  - From Nathan Godfrey, Jr. to Nathaniel Adams Jr., 1774
  - From Daniel and Mary Morehouse to Nathaniel Addams, 1783
  - From Abigail Morehous to Nathaniel Adams, 1783
- Deeds, 1783-1797; Box I, Folder C; 17.0 items
  - From Nathan and Hannah Bennitt to Nathaniel Adams, 1784
  - From Gideon and Ann Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1784
  - From Joseph Hanford to Nathaniel Adams, 1784
  - From Stephen and Mary Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1784
  - From Seth Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1786
  - From Joseph Wakeman, et al. to Nathaniel Adams, 1788
  - From Joseph Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1788
  - From Samuel and Elizabeth Downs to Nathaniel Adams, 1790
  - From Samuel Downs to Nathaniel Adams, 1790
  - From Hezekiah Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1790, 1797; 2.0 items
  - From Sarah and Lucy Marven to Nathaniel Adams, 1790
  - From Nathan Wakeman to Nathaniel Adams, 1792
  - From Jonathan and Lucy Coley to Nathaniel Adams, 1793
  - From Hannah Bennitt to Nathaniel Adams, 1796
  - From Thomas and Abigail Davis to Nathaniel Adams, 1797
  - From Stephen B. Hanford to Nathaniel Adams, 1797
- Deeds, 1800-1854; Box I, Folder D; 18.0 items
  - From Joseph Hanford to Joseph Adams, 1800
  - From Jonathan Ogden to Joseph Adams, 1803, 1805; 2.0 items
  - From Jonathan and Rebeckah Ogden to Joseph Adams, 1803
  - From Joseph and Sarah Hanford to Joseph Adams, 1803
  - From Salome Adams to Joseph Adams, 1805
  - From John Goreham to Joseph Adams, 1807
  - From Anne Adams to Joseph Adams, 1808
  - From Nathaniel Adams to Joseph Adams, 1810
  - From Daniel Coley to Joseph Adams, 1812
  - From Abigail Adams to Joseph Adams, 1813
  - From Nathaniel Adams to Joseph Adams, 1814
  - From Jonathan and Rebeckah Ogden, et al. to Joseph Adams, 1815
  - From Ann Adams to Joseph Adams, 1816
  - From William and Ann Nichols to Joseph Adams, 1818
  - From Walter and Mirenda Banks to Joseph Adams, 1819
  - From Joseph and Sarah Adams to Ebenezer B. Adams, 1841
  - From John S. and Harriet L. Hyde to Joseph Adams, 1854
- Legal Papers, Box I, Folder E; 26.0 items
  - Probate Papers
    - Nathan Addams Jr., 1723-1724
    - Nathaniel Adams, 1784-1814; 8.0 items
    - Joseph Adams, 1869-1873; 3.0 items
    - Abigail Hanford, Nathaniel Adams, executor, 1782
  - Writs
    - Zebulon Fanton vs. Jonathan Adams, 1772
    - Nathaniel Adams vs. Abraham Hays, 1773
    - Nathan Adams vs. Samuel Taylor, 1773
    - Nathaniel Adams vs. Gershom Stevens, 1774
    - Nathaniel Adams vs. Stephen Guyer, 1780
  - Petition of Obediah Wright against Ebenezer Adams, et al., 1809
  - Nathaniel Adams list for 1800
  - Produce contract between Nathaniel Adams and Stephen Guyer, 1789
  - Contract for negro boy named Amos between Joseph Hanford and Nathaniel Adams Jr.
  - House deed from Peter Williams to Joseph Adams, 1825
  - Fence division between Nathaniel Adams and Samuel Silliman, 1767
  - Land division to Nathaniel Adams from the Committee, 1749
  - Payment for stone from Nathaniel Adams, 1786
- Bills and Bills Receipted, 1773-1784; Box I, Folder F; 51.0 items
  - Nathaniel Adams, 1784-1817; 17.0 items
  - Ebenezer B. Adams, 1851-1869; 8.0 items
  - Joseph Adams, 1773-1817; 25.0 items
  - Mrs. Adams, 1813
- Financial Papers, Correspondence and Maps, Box I, Folder G; 41.0 items
  - Financial Papers
    - Bank notes of the Saugatuck Bank, 1862-1864; 10.0 items
    - Bank notes of the First National Bank of Westport, 1864-1872; 7.0 items
    - Promissory notes to Joseph Adams and others, 1805-1865; 7.0 items
  - Correspondence to
    - Nathaniel Adams, 1784, 1788; 2.0 items
    - Joseph Adams, 1803
    - Bartlett Bondage re: Nathaniel Adams' sheep bill, 1763
    - Mrs. Adams, 1889; 2.0 items
    - Mr. E. B. Adams, 1865
    - Cousin and Brother and Sister, n.d., 1844; 2.0 items
  - Maps
    - Saw Mill lot, n.d.
    - Piece of land belonging to daughters of Nathaniel Adams in Jennings Woods, surveyed by Gideon Wells, 1764
- Account Books, Box I, Folder H; 6.0 items
  - Nathaniel Adams, farm and store accounts, 1762-1782, 1784-1790; 2.0 items
  - Nathaniel Adams accounts due (including spinning), 1803
  - Joseph Adams surveyor's books, 1806, 1829; 2.0 items
  - Joseph Adams store book, 1802-1803
- Account Book, Box I, Folder I; 1.0 item
  - Eli Adams (1784-1861) account book including store and general account with notes, 1811-1815
- Adams Genealogy written by Edward Bradford Adams, Box II, Folder A